One of the great benefits of a computer is that you're able to do with it whatever you want.
You can browse social media, play video games or watch a movie.
For many devices, however, this isn't the case.
You can only install an app on your iPhone if Apple lets you.
The Oculus Quest 2 can just break down if Facebook blocks you.
And your Samsung camera may just break down forever if you take a look inside the phone.
Sellers of electronic devices have grown to the mindset that
an electronic devices should be more loyal to them than it is to you.
But if you bought the device, you are the owner.
Only you should decide how the device operates.
Being in charge of your own device is called software autonomy.
You should be able to uninstall Google News if you don't use it.
Apple shouldn't be able to install spyware onto your phone if you don't want that.
Software autonomy gives you the right to wipe your phone completely
and to install on it whatever you want.
It is your device, so you're in charge.
Support software autonomy by reading more on the Digital Justice website.